vivaldi.com 2016-04-24

# Privacy Policy – Vivaldi

## General

At Vivaldi Technologies AS (“Vivaldi”), protecting your privacy is one of our top priorities. We strictly protect the security of your personal information within Vivaldi’s Web sites. We do not share or sell your data with any 3rd party and protect user data from disclosure, with exceptions only requested by law or court order.

## Types of data we collect and its purpose

Vivaldi may collect visitor statistics. The visitor statistics may include information about the visitors IP-addresses, usage patterns, the point in time the visitor visits our web sites on vivaldi.net and vivaldi.com and information about the browser and operating system the visitor uses. This information is solely for statistical purpose and is not used to identify individuals. We use these statistics to improve and optimize usability of our products and services for our users. These statistics help us determine where we need to improve and prioritize our resources accordingly.

The web sites may use cookies. A cookie is a tiny data file that resides on your computer, mobile phone, or other device, and allows us to recognize you as a visitor when you return to the website using the same computer and web browser. This allows us to provide more customized experience for our visitor. You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser. We keep the contact information you provide us with, in your account profile. We may use your contact information to inform you about important information concerning our services. Additionally, we may contact you for our other products and services. You can always opt out of receiving these types of emails from us.

## Access

Vivaldi has strict restrictions on access to user data. Only a limited number of Vivaldi’s employees or employees at Vivaldi’s service providers for the web hosting services have access.

## Transfer

Vivaldi cooperates with Advania data centers (see <http://www.advania.com/datacentres/>) for the hosting and running of the Vivaldi websites. Advania data centers will process and handle personal data on Vivaldi’s behalf in accordance with this Privacy Statement, and in accordance with applicable laws and regulations. Vivaldi will not transfer any personal data to any third party except as required by law or law enforcement.

## Web search partners

Some of the web search services provided herein are provided by Vivaldi.rocks and powered by Vivaldi.rocks partners. For information on the web search services data collection, please visit <http://info.vivaldi.rocks/privacy-policy/>, and the search providers privacy policy as applicable, which is incorporated into this Privacy Statement by reference.

## Retention and deletion

Vivaldi will delete personal information when all purposes of the personal-information processing have been fulfilled and when deletion is allowed pursuant to applicable laws and regulations.

## Reviews

Procedures are reviewed regularly to ensure that the policies are followed. Any non-conformance regarding the policies will be corrected without unnecessary delay.

## Updates and changes

This Privacy Statement may be updated or changed. When we post changes to this Privacy Statement, we will include the date when the Privacy Statement was last updated. If there are material changes to this statement or in how we will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification.

## Contact information

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, or privacy on our Web sites, we can be reached at contact[at]vivaldi.net.
